So, you a little bit about spec driven
development just now. Um, what do I mean
by prompt chaos kind of in contrast to
that? Well, if you're here, I'm assuming
that you've worked with an with a coding
agent before. Um, at the very least with
an LLM and you know that the primary
interface for these things still
is chat. Uh, you might give a little
request. You say, "I want something."
Your agent says, "Yes, okay." Gives you
some code. You say, "Thank you, but not
quite." Your agent's like, "Okay." And
it gives you some more code. And this is
an important process. This conversation
is important. Like something key is
happening here. You're figuring out what
it is you actually want to build. And
maybe you had a perfectly granular idea
of what that was initially,
but maybe now you have to work through
or around something that the agent can
or can't do, or you discover something
in the process of building it, and
you're like, "Okay, maybe actually I'll
do it this way."
Really, what's happening here is that
you and your agent are speaking two
different languages.
You're speaking the language of intent
and your agent is speaking the language
of implementation
which is code. Um how many of you are
software developers?
So how many of you think that writing
more code is always the way to solve a
problem?
Excellent. Great. Okay. The answer is
that's never really the answer, right?
But that's the only language that your
agent speaks. And importantly, your side
of this conversation is ephemeral. It's
not important. It's designed to be
disposed of. Some agents literally put
this conversation in your temp folder,
never to be seen again. And what you're
left with is a big ball of
implementation
code.
And somewhere in there is your intent.
But code can't really tell you why it's
there necessarily. It can't say I'm a
loadbearing aspect of the author's
intent for this program or I'm just here
because uh the author had to hack around
something. I'm not really that
important. You can refactor me if you
want. Kind of can't tell you that. If
you don't document what your intent was,
it will be assumed.
And I think historically
like that's kind of okay because humans
have a lot of ways to correctly assume
things. That's why some of us have
evolved so well. Um not Simon. He'll get
there.
>> You're looking at me.
>> Sorry.
Um one of the ways that we assume intent
is by using stuff.
Uh take this haird dryer for example.
I took this picture and I asked an LLM
to make me a sleeker, more modern haird
dryer and they gave me this and I like
it. I think it's sleek and modern and I
like it. However, there are a couple of
functional issues here and they're
subtle. That little rubber knob on the
side keeps the haird dryer from slipping
off the counter. Handy. that sleek
little slider. Cool. Until you have like
hair products or water on your hands and
then it gets sticky over time and it's
impossible to use. Annoying LLMs
famously hairless for now. They don't
know this. They'll never use a haird
dryer. They don't understand.
The same is true in code. Here's a field
validation function for a form.
If you've never made a form before,
you're probably like, "What is that set
timeout doing there?" Um, until you use
the form and if it's if it's not there
immediately when you type your first
character, it's like, "That's not a
valid email." And you're like, "Yeah, I
understand that M is not a valid email.
Thank you."
LM don't care about this either, right?
They don't use forms in the same way.
They'll happily strip stuff like this
out. Now, this is a really trivial UX
example, but imagine a codebase with a
really wide surface area. This kind of
stuff is going to compound over time,
and this is the most frustrating kind of
drift that there is because this is the
kind of stuff that you already thought
about and solved at some point, and your
agent was like, "Don't care. Not
important."
You might be thinking to yourself, we've
always kind of had this problem, like we
haven't always documented intent. That's
not really what we do as software
developers. We write code. Intent and
context comes around in things like
meeting notes, passing conversations
over coffee,
documentation, code comments. If you
work somewhere that you know cares about
keeping these things up to date,
my point is that now we kind of have all
that stuff plus these agent
conversations and that's really
compounding the problem because that's
just you and your agent. And again,
these are disposable uh conversations.
So, as well, the consumers of your
codebase are changing. They're evolving.
Uh whether we like it or not, they are
evolving. Of course, other developers
are going to see your code. Um
but increasingly people who don't code
are going to see it or approach it. That
might sound like sci-fi. It's not
sci-fi. It's happening now. Um, I
literally just heard the co-founder of
the intercom, for example, say that 100%
of their designers are expected to push
code to production today, even if they
have never written a line of code
before.
Pause for booze. That's been getting
booze, by the way, from the crowd.
People are scared by this. I understand.
Um, agents are seeing your codebase.
Agents are pretty smart, but they don't
work autonomously. They need you to
help. They need a human to be their tech
lead. And so when I say agents are
consuming your codebase, I really mean
people leaving agents. And those people
don't really want to read every line of
your code. Even if they want to, they're
probably not going to. Also, you in
three months, uh, if you've ever
vibrated something and then come back to
it like a couple months later, you're
like, well, who was she? I have no idea.
And that might not even be three months.
That might be like two hours.
So, how do we inoculate ourselves
against this problem?
I think the answer is to design a
narrative arc for your codebase
in natural language. And I'm going to
explain a little bit more about what I
mean by that. But I think there's been a
lot of sort of industry convergence on
this idea of spec driven development. Um
you have a bunch of tools that do this
now. You've got Kira by AWS.
Um Speckit by GitHub obviously Tesla
that Simon is showing. I feel the
existence of all these things really
concede my point which is that natural
language is now a first class citizen in
your codebase. Um and if it's not it
really needs to be kind of is whether
you capture it or not.
So how do you do that?
I think a perfectly defensible way to
get started is to just start heavily
annotating stuff. Like this is kind of
the simplest example I could imagine. Um
this by the way is a module for uh
storage in a broader notes application.
And this annotation
kind of explains what it does, who calls
it, what the downstream effects are.
It's pretty compact. If you wanted to
get the same amount of context only by
reading the code, you would have to
traverse quite a lot of files and quite
a lot of lines of code to get the same
information. So that annotation is doing
a lot of heavy lifting there, not just
for agents who approach your card base,
but for people maybe you're working
somewhere that kind of already does
this. And I think that's nice. That
gives you a huge head start.
I want to make the case though that
specs will do a lot of this heavy
lifting as well. Um, here's an example
of the same module and this is a spec.
I've done this in a couple of parts
because I want you to be able to see the
whole thing and I hope you can see that.
Um,
but this is an example of a spec that I
generated with Tessle
and I feel it has a couple of important
loadbearing pieces. So, it's got kind of
a highle, can you see my cursor? Yeah.
Okay. It's got kind of a highle overview
at the top of what exactly this is.
It's got a generate tag. This is like
Tesla specific syntax that links to the
file um to the code files, the
implementation file that this is
describing. And we've got capabilities
that are enumerated
as testable statements in natural
language. If I wanted to, I could have
like a test per line here, but that's
not how I chose to write this. I chose
to use the at test syntax, which is
going to create a test based on these
things that I've described here at that
location.
I've got an API. Um, you saw this in
Simon's example as well. This is just
the interface that I wanted to use. And
then importantly, I feel like this is
really the part that illustrates my
point. This describes all of the other
things that this module interacts with
that this this spec needs in order to be
built in full. In this case, all of
these things, all of these at use tags
are pointing to other specs.
Um, but they could just as well be like
internal modules, code files,
decision documents, I don't know, um,
external libraries, things like that.
The important thing I feel is the file
linking, which might feel trivial, but
it's actually what keeps our specs from
getting super super drifted from their
implementation. Like specs are all well
and good, but what are they talking
about?
Here's an example of how I organize that
program and like how where the specs
live. And this is just one example. I
feel just like in code, separation of
concerns is kind of a good idea when it
comes to specs. I also feel uh that
smaller scoped specs are better, produce
better code, produce better results. But
this is totally up to you. This whole
program could have been one spec, one
giant spec. This is how I chose to to
kind of design that arc of the program.
And that leaves me with something that
looks more like this. Yes, I still have
all of the same implementation code, but
it's much easier for me to understand
what the author intended for this
program because I have in natural
language exactly what I expect it to do.
What about existing projects? It's kind
of nice to talk about specs for like
Greenfield stuff and stuff that you
know, you know, you have it in your mind
exactly how it's going to work, but a
lot of us work on legacy code bases
um or just old projects. I think the the
bottom line is what you can do literally
now is pre prevent
prevent regression from this point on
which is still important.
Um and I would think about
kind of working backwards from your
implementation code and kind of trying
to get the intent out of any source that
it's available. Where is intent already
captured? things like tests, integration
tests, regression tests, uh end to end
tests, not necessarily unit tests where
we're like
inputs, outputs, whatever. Um it's less
about the functionality and it's more
about what is the path the user is
taking or the caller. Um decision docs,
userfacing docs, PRs, maybe
conversations in PRs, commit logs, stuff
like that. Slack conversations. Um,
it's very hard to export stuff out of
Slack, so good luck with that. Agent
conversation history, uh, is a really
good one.
Okay. Um, I'm bored of this
presentation. Let's play a game.
Where is it? Here it is. Should we
scroll through Simon's WhatsApp?
>> Will you guys play hanging in with me?
Do we have time?
>> Yeah. Can Can you give me a letter?
>> E
>> S T
>> because
>> L
M C
uh P
>> Y
>> Great job. Great job. Um round of
applause for you guys. Anyway, this is
the hangman app that I vcoded
and what I decided to do was fake a spec
for it because I coded this n amount of
months ago. Um, and I wanted to see if I
still understood how it worked.
So, I used something um that Tesla
offers called the document tool. This is
actually taking code and inferring a
spec from it. And in this case, I don't
know if you can see exactly what I've
done. I grabbed my chat block. I made
this with uh Gemini. Um, and I grabbed
my chat log and I added an extra prompt
here. I just said, I'm going to give you
my chat log. Can you make sure that all
the core decisions that came about in
that conversation are captured here?
And I did this twice. Once without that
context and once with it.
Here's an example of one piece of that
spec with the extra context. Um, so you
guys weren't interacting with the app,
but one of the things I cared about was
it has to be like keyboard first. I want
it to be you type the letters and then
the letters that's that's your guess.
And you can see user guesses letters by
typing. At the very end, you see
alphabet buttons are also clickable.
It's kind of like an afterthought. Yeah,
because I meant for the keyboard to be
the primary interaction modality without
the extra context. This is that same
capability enumerated. It's like
clickable alphabet buttons also handles
keyboard input because it's describing
the functionality of the thing, right?
It's less about the intent for the
user's interaction with my with my
incredible groundbreaking app. I am
fundraising, by the way.
So, I guess what I want to leave you
with is this phrase that you've heard
10,000 times in the last two years,
which is that this is a new era of
software development. It's cliche, but
it's cliche for a reason. It's cliche
because it's true. Um,
and it's important for humans to quickly
to be able to quickly understand
implementation code so that they can act
as this tech lead for agents. It's also
important for agents to understand their
working environment. Um, and I feel that
documenting intent really does that and
kind of future proofs your codebase and
your implementation.
That's all I have for you. Thank you.